Chris Coenen Collection on General Tom Thumb MS254
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Cartes-de-visite, 1858 -- 1940; MS254.000519
  - Noah Orr; Barnum Giant; info on back, 1870; MS254.000811 (Box 20)
    Orr played the "Giant" in many of the plays with the little people
  - Isaac Sprague and wife and child; Skeleton Man, 1870; MS254.000812 (Box 20)
    Isaac was a thin man who was often photographed with his family
  - Jennie Quigley; 19 years old; Doane, Delevan, WIsc., 1869; MS254.000813 (Box 20)
    Jennie showing her ankle
  - Jennie Quigley; 21 yars old; Doane, Delevan, Wisc., 1871; MS254.000814 (Box 20)
    Doane was Jennie's favorite photographer
  - Jennie Quigley; 22 years old, hand colored; Doane, Delevan, Wisc., 1872; MS254.000815 (Box 20)
    Jennie was born in 1850
  - Jennie Quigley; 24 years old; Whitney, Chicago, 1874; MS254.000816 (Box 20)
    Part of a series done by Whitney
  - Jennie Quigley; double Jennie; 24 years old; Whitney, Chicago, 1874; MS254.000817 (Box 20)
    24 years old and 30 inches in height
  - Jennie Quigley; rear double Jennie; 24 years old; Whitney, Chicago, 1874; MS254.000818 (Box 20)
    Jennie from the back
  - Annie Nelson; age 21; Wilkes, Baltimore, 1886; MS254.000819 (Box 20)
    Annie was a friend of the Strattons and performed with them
  - Edwin Newell as Gen, Grant, Jr., 1863; MS254.000820 (Box 20)
    Edwin Newell went on to do a skating act and married Minnie Warren; he ramarried after her death and had two children; he died in 1915
  - Edwin Newell and man; Anthony, NY, 1867; MS254.000821 (Box 20)
    Newell performed at Barnum's Museum before it burned
  - Edwin Newell and chair; Anthony, NY, 1870; MS254.000822 (Box 20)
    Posed next to a chair for scale
  - Lucy and Sarah Adams with a man; age 20 and 18; Eisenmann, NY; signed, 1871; MS254.000823 (Box 20)
    The Adams Sisters were from Martha's Vinyard and were friends of Lavinia; they usually signed their cards as "Adams Sisters"
  - Lucy and Sarah Adams; age 20 and 18; Eisenmann, NY; signed, 1871; MS254.000824 (Box 20)
    Same sitting as 389
  - Lucy and Sarah Adams; age 20 and 18; Eisenmann, NY; signed, 1871; MS254.000825 (Box 20)
    Variation of 390
  - Ernesto Magri and family with Primo Magri; Warren, Boston, 1880; MS254.000826 (Box 20)
    Newly arrived from Europe; the family would eventually return to Italy
  - Leopold Kahn; Admiral Dot; with WB Harrison; Gihon and Thompson, Philadelphia, 1871; MS254.000827 (Box 20)
    Kahn was born in San Farancisco and met and was hired by Barnum. He eventually ran a hotel in White Plains, NY and died in 1918 of Flu
  - Leopold Kahn; Admiral Dot at thirteen with WB Harrison; Anthony, NY, 1871; MS254.000828 (Box 20)
    WB Harrison worked for Barnum as an actor and was a friend of the Strattons
  - Zoe Meleke, Circassian; autographed; Wood, NY, 1877; MS254.000829 (Box 20)
    Zoe started out as a "Circassian Woman" with frizzy hair; she later developed a bird act and toured with Lavinia's company
  - Zoe Meleke, Circassian; autographed, 1880; MS254.000830 (Box 20)
    Zoe toured with many companies
  - Zoe Meleke; Circassian; Wood, NY, 1877; MS254.000831 (Box 20)
    hand colored
  - Australian General Tom Thumb; Sarony, Scarborough, 1871; MS254.000832 (Box 20)
    The Tom Thumb group travelled to Australia on their world tour; there were plenty of imitators
  - Australian General Tom Thumb; Oldham & Angle, Colchester, Australia?, 1871; MS254.000833 (Box 20)
    Anothe view of "The Original Australian General Tom Thumb"
  - Col. Routh Goshen; giant; Lord, NY; autographed, 1865; MS254.000834 (Box 20)
    Goshen was a giant that worked for Barnum and often appeared with little people as a "giant" in plays
  - Millie-Christine McCoy; Siamese twins; Ollivier, NY, 1882; MS254.000835 (Box 20)
    Millie-Christine were born into slavery; eventually brought The Italian Midgets to the US
  - Lizzie Reed showing ankle; autographed, 1865; MS254.000836 (Box 20)
    Lizzie worked with Barnum and many companies; often confused with Lavinia Warren
  - Charles and Eliza Nestel, 1882; MS254.000837 (Box 20)
    Charles and Eliza Nestel were contemporaries of Charles and Lavinia; possible autograph
  - Tintype; sixth plate with mat; Lavinia Warren (Mercy Lavinia Warren Bump): Digital Copy only, 1859; MS254.000838 (Box 20)
    Early tintype portrait of Lavinia, pre-1860, showing some ankle: original in Coenen Collection
  - Tintype of Tom Thumb in yachting outfit; copy of a cdv, 1880; MS254.000839 (Box 20)
    Copy of an earlier photo of Tom Thumb in his yachting outfit
  - Gem tintype of Tom Thumb; copy, 1864; MS254.000840 (Box 20)
    Gem size copy of a cdv
  - Gem tintype copy of Lavinia Warren, 1864; MS254.000841 (Box 20)
  - Gem tintype copy of Commodore Nutt, 1864; MS254.000842 (Box 20)
  - Tintype copy of a cdv; wedding series, 1863 -- 1865; MS254.000843 (Box 20)
    Copy of a cdv; reversed beacause a tintype is really a negative
  - Albert Smith,author; Silvy, Bayswater, London, 1865; MS254.000844 (Box 20)
    Albert Smith wrote a play, Hop-O-My_Thumb, for Tom Thumb in the 1850's
  - Tom Thumb and PT Barnum, LSC, London, 1858; MS254.000845 (Box 20)
    Part of a stereo made in 1858
  - Tom Thumb House in Middleboro, Ma. 1937, MS254.000846 (Box 20)
    A silverprint snapshot of the Tom Thumb House in 1937
  - Snapshot of Tom Thumb House in Middleboro 1937, MS254.000847 (Box 20)
  - Copy of painting of Tom Thumb, 1940; MS254.000848 (Box 20)
    Later silverprint copy of a young Tom Thumb circa 1848
  - Wild Men of Borneo, Waino & Plutano, 1865; MS254.000849 (Box 20)
    The Davis Brothers were from the US and were short, mentally retarded but quite strong; billed as being captured in the South Seas
  - Admiral Dot in Character; Leopold Kahn, 1865; MS254.000850 (Box 20)
    Worked for Barnum and many companies; retired to White Plains, NY
  - Admiral Dot as Drummer, 1865; MS254.000851 (Box 20)
  - Sarah Belton, 1870; MS254.000852 (Box 20)
    Sarah appeared in many Companies
  - Jennie Quigley, young, 1862; MS254.000853 (Box 20)
  - Anna Swan with midget Colvin; Barnum Museum tax stamp, 1865; MS254.000854 (Box 20)
    Anna holding up the dwarf Colvin
  - Chang & Eng Bunker; original Siamese Twins, 1865; MS254.000855 (Box 20)
    They worked for Barnum briefly after the CivilWar
  - Millie-Christine McCoy; Siamese twins, 1865; MS254.000856 (Box 20)
    They helped bring Primo and Ernesto to the US
  - Col. Routh Goshen; giant; Lord, NY; autographed, 1865; MS254.000857 (Box 20)
    Worked for Barnum and many companies of dwarves as the Giant
  - Noah Orr with Lizzie Read, 1865; MS254.000858 (Box 20)
    Both worked at Barnum's Museum
  - Madge Kendal, British actress; befriended Elephant Man, 1875; MS254.000859 (Box 20)
    A popular British actress; she was introduced to John Merrick and they became friends
  - Paris, Fr.;Porte St. Marin Blvd., 1872; MS254.000860 (Box 20)
    Paris as Charles and Lavinia would have experienced it
  - Paris, Fr.;Porte St. Marin Blvd., 1865; MS254.000861 (Box 20)
  - Blarney Castle, Dublin, Ireland, 1870; MS254.000862 (Box 20)
    Tom and Lavinia visited and Tom kissed the Blarney Stone; Lavinia was afraid they might drop him
  - Royal Family of Britain, 1865; MS254.000863 (Box 20)
    Tom and Later Tom and Lavinia made many visits to the Royal Family
  - Windsor Castle, 1865; MS254.000864 (Box 20)
    Tom visited the Royals at Windsor
  - Buckingham Palace, London, 1865; MS254.000865 (Box 20)
    Tom and Barnum;s first visit with the Queen was at Buckingham Palace
- Printed ephemera, 1835 -- 1996; MS254.000866
  This series contains printed ephemera related to Tom Thumb, including postcards, advertisements, lithographs, prints, fliers, event programs, clippings, and engravings. Subjects of these materials include Tom Thumb, Lavinia Warren, Count Primo Magri, Ernesto Magri, Tom Thumb's carriage and wedding, the Tom Thumb Show and other performances, and Tom Thumb and Lavinia Warren's activities and travels.
  - General Tom Thumb print, circa 1850 -- 1880; MS254.001.001.00001; 0.1 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jumbo photographs, cards, and prints, circa 1880 -- 1975; MS254.001.001.00002; 0.1 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 2)
    This file contains two photographs of Jumbo in Barnum Hall and one photograph of the fire at Barnum Hall in 1975; a print titled "Jumbo at work and play;" and cards of Jumbo in various scenes.
  - Ringling Brothers and Barnum and Bailey Circus program, 1975; MS254.001.001.00003; 0.1 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The World of Phineas T. Barnum photograph portfolio, 1977; MS254.001.001.00004; 0.2 Linear Feet (Box 1)
    This file contains a portfolio of print reproductions of portrait photographs originally taken by Matthew Brady of members of Barnum's troupe, including dancer Ernestine de Faiber, General Tom Thumb and his wife Lavinia Warren Bumpus, James Murphy (the "Irish Giant"), Anna Swan (the "Nova Scotia Giantess"), Jane Campbell (the "Fat Lady"), Isaac Sprague (the "Living Skeleton"), Mrs. Myers (first name unknown, the "Bearded Lady"), and Siamese twins Chang and Eng.
  - RPPC (Real Photo Post Card); Bump Family homestead, Plymouth St., Middleboro, 1918; MS254.000867 (Box 3)
    Bump homestead
  - RPPC; Tom Thumb House, Middleboro, 1908; MS254.000868 (Box 3)
    Charles Stratton had this house built around 1870 across the street from the Bump homestead; many of the features accomodated their small stature
  - RPPC; Tom Thumb House, Middleboro; later, 1915; MS254.000869 (Box 3)
    Slightly later view of the house
  - RPPC; Lavinia and Primo in front of Primo's Pastime, Middleboro, 1915; MS254.000870 (Box 3)
    Primo and Lavinia opened a little variety store and ice cream shop near their home in Middleboro
  - RPPC; Lavinia and Primo in front of Primo's Pastime, Middleboro II; info on back, 1917; MS254.000871 (Box 3)
    Variation of 593 with info on back
  - RPPC; Lavinia and Primo in front of Primo's Pastime III, 1917; MS254.000872 (Box 3)
    Variation of 593
  - RPPC; Lavinia and Primo in front of Primo's Pastime IV, 1917; MS254.000873 (Box 3)
    Variation of 593 with message on back
  - Primo, Lavinia and Ernesto at Royaume de Lilliput, Paris; autographed, 1906; MS254.000874 (Box 3)
    Signed by Lavinia
  - Primo, Lavinia and Ernesto at Royaume de Lilliput, Paris; autographed II, 1906; MS254.000875 (Box 3)
    Signed by Lavinia and Primo
  - Primo, Lavinia at Royaume de Lilliput,Paris, 1906; MS254.000876 (Box 3)
    Lilliput
  - Nouma Hava at Royaume de Lilliput, 1906; MS254.000877 (Box 3)
    Another little person
  - Paulus and Hubler at Royaume de Lilliput, 1906; MS254.000878 (Box 3)
    Dwarf policemen
  - Fire brigade; Royaume de Lilliput, Paris, 1906; MS254.000879 (Box 3)
    Little fire wagon
  - Carriage; Royaume de Lilliput, 1906; MS254.000880 (Box 3)
    Fancy coach
  - Lilliput, Village de Nains, 1910; MS254.000881 (Box 3)
    Coach and driver
  - Primo and Lavinia at Tiny-Town, Olympia Annex, 1908; MS254.000882 (Box 3)
    Lavinia and Primo had a booth where they sold trinkets
  - Lavinia and Primo's residence; Midget City, Dreamland, Coney Island, NY, 1905; MS254.000883 (Box 3)
    Mrs. General Tom Thumb and Count Magri spent the summer of 1905 at Coney Island
  - Lavinia and Primo's residence; Midget City, Dreamland, Coney Island, NY; autographed, 1905; MS254.000884 (Box 3)
    They often signed these postcards at the bottom
  - RPPC; Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto; At Theatre Comique, Feb. 1911, MS254.000885 (Box 3)
    Advertising a show
  - Count and Baron Magri in Middleboro, 1910; MS254.000886 (Box 3)
    Walking in Middleboro
  - RPPC: Same as 609, 1910; MS254.000887 (Box 3)
  - RPPC; Count and Countess Magri with bicycle in Middleboro, 1911; MS254.000888 (Box 3)
    Lavinia and Primo in Middleboro; Meassage on back says, "Thought you would like to see the little couple, they spend their summers here mostly."
  - Count and Countess Magri with bicycle, Middleboro, 1911; MS254.000889 (Box 3)
    Same as 612
  - Lavinia and Primo standing in their yard, Middleboro, 1910; MS254.000890 (Box 3)
    Standing in their yard on a windy day
  - Primo and Ernesto at large doors; probably Middleboro, 1910; MS254.000891 (Box 3)
    Before the doors of a large building
  - Center Street, Middleboro; Ernesto in front of The Frank Stores, 1910; MS254.000892 (Box 3)
    Advertising postcard made by J.H. Frank
  - RPPC; Mrs. General Tom Thumb and Party, Longmont, Colorado, 1908; MS254.000893 (Box 3)
    Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto at Longmont Commercial Association Exhibit Hildreth
  - Same as 616; printed card from Longmont, Colorado, 1908; MS254.000894 (Box 3)
    Printed version of 616
  - RPPC; Lavinia Warren in fancy dress, 1912; MS254.000895 (Box 3)
    Lavinia at 71
  - Mrs. General Tom Thumb in her 71st year; similar to 618, 1912; MS254.000896 (Box 3)
  - RPPC; Lavinia and her brother and nephew, 1912; MS254.000897 (Box 3)
    Lavinia and, most likely, one of her brothers and a nephew, maybe Benjamin Bump
  - Rppc; Overview of Middleboro, Ma. circa 1918, MS254.000898 (Box 3)
    This is Middleboro as Lavinia would have seen it near the end of her life
  - Main St Looking South, Middleboro, Mass., 1911; MS254.000899 (Box 3)
    Main St.
  - South Main St., looking North, Middleboro, Mass., 1913; MS254.000900 (Box 3)
    South Main St.
  - South Main St., Residential Section, Middleboro, Mass., 1913; MS254.000901 (Box 3)
    Residential
  - Center St., Middleboro, Mass., 1911; MS254.000902 (Box 3)
    Center St.
  - Center St., Middleboro, Mass., 1919; MS254.000903 (Box 3)
  - N.Y.N.H. & H.R.R. Staion, Middleboro, Mass., 1909; MS254.000904 (Box 3)
    Lavinia and others would have used this railroad station to travel to Bidgeport or NYC
  - Public Library, Middleboro, Mass., 1909; MS254.000905 (Box 3)
    There are several large oil paintings of some of the little people on display
  - First Cong. Church, Middleboro, Mass., 1915; MS254.000906 (Box 3)
    This was the church Lavinia attended as a child; near their home in Middleboro
  - The Old Green Congregational Church at Middleboro Centre, Middleboro, Mass., 1910; MS254.000907 (Box 3)
    Lavinia's childhood church
  - Nemasket Hill Cemetery,Middleboro, Mass., 1915; MS254.000908 (Box 3)
    The Bump family plot is here; Minnie and her child are buried here
  - Nemasket Hill Cemetery, the Main Drive, ,Middleboro, Mass., 1915; MS254.000909 (Box 3)
  - Staple's Shore, Lake Assawampsett, Middleboro, Mass., 1915; MS254.000910 (Box 3)
    Resort in Middleboro
  - Troop A, Wareham St., Middleboro, Mass., 1913; MS254.000911 (Box 3)
    The troops on way to camp; Wareham St. (just passed bridge at Nemasket River); August, 1913; Lavinia was very patriotic and helped the troops and war effort
  - Former home of PT Barnum, Bridgeport, Ct.; Windermere, 1905; MS254.000912 (Box 3)
    One of Barnum's later homes in Bridgeport
  - Former home of PT Barnum, Bridgeport, Ct.; Windermere II, 1910; MS254.000913 (Box 3)
  - Barnum Institute of Science and History, Bridgeport; now Barnum Museum, 1905; MS254.000914 (Box 3)
    Barnum donated this building to Bridgeport
  - Entrance to Mountain Grove Cemetery, Bridgeport, 1905; MS254.000915 (Box 3)
    Resting place of Barnum (1893), Charles Stratton (1883) and Lavinia Warren (1919)
  - NY, NH, & H Railroad Station, Bridgeport, Ct., 1906; MS254.000916 (Box 3)
    Barnum and others would have used this station
  - Steamer Bidgeport, Bridgeport Harbor, Conn., 1910; MS254.000917 (Box 3)
    Many people took the steamer from Bridgeport to NY
  - Harbor Scene, Bridgeport, Conn., 1910; MS254.000918 (Box 3)
    Busy harbor
  - Mohawk Yacht Club and Harbor, Bridgeport, Conn., 1910; MS254.000919 (Box 3)
    Charles Stratton was an avid sailor and probably frequented some of the yacht clubs
  - Park City Yacht Club, Bridgeport, Conn., 1910; MS254.000920 (Box 3)
  - Bridgeport Yacht Club,Bridgeport, Conn., 1912; MS254.000921 (Box 3)
  - Artists copy of a dageurreotype of Tom Thumb's First Visit to St. Louis, 1846 -- 1990; MS254.000922 (Box 3)
    The card says it was taken in 1842, which seems a bit early; original dag is in Mo. Hist. Soc.
  - Copy of half-plate dag of Tom Thumb and unknown man, 1848 -- 1990; MS254.000923 (Box 3)
    Copy of an earlier dag
  - Copy of Dag of Tom Thumb, 1848 -- 1990; MS254.000924 (Box 3)
    Copy of dag at the Barnum Museum
  - Stereo of Tom Thumb in his carriage; LSC,; London, 1858 -- 1990; MS254.000925 (Box 3)
    Tom in his carriage
  - Tom Thumb's court dress; Somers Hist. Soc., 1990; MS254.000926 (Box 3)
    Supposedly, Tom Thumb's court suit worn during his 1844 visit with Queen Victoria
  - Portrait of Tom Thumb as Napoleon taken from a dag at the Barnum Museum, 1954; MS254.000927 (Box 3)
    Painted by Leslie Fairchild
  - Mrs. Tom Thumb, 1875 -- 1990; MS254.000928 (Box 3)
    From Middleboro Hist. Soc.
  - General Tom Thumb, 1875 -- 1990; MS254.000929 (Box 3)
  - Dag of PT Barnum and Tom Thumb at NPG, 1850 -- 1994; MS254.000930 (Box 3)
    Root dag of the two
  - Tom Thumb carriage; Hertzberg Circus Collection, 1971; MS254.000931 (Box 3)
    Carriage in San Antonio
  - Tom Thumb carriage; Hertzberg Circus Collection II, 1977; MS254.000932 (Box 3)
  - Minature Circus, Hertzberg, 1971; MS254.000933 (Box 3)
    Miniature circus
  - Currier and Ives lithograph copy, MS254.000934 (Box 3)
    Tom on chair
  - Tom Thumb Carriage, Circus Hall of Fame, Sarasota, 1970; MS254.000935 (Box 3)
    Supposedly, Tom Thumb's carriage given by Queen Victoria in 1854
  - Pasha Hayati Hassid- The Turkish Tom Thumb; UK, 1910; MS254.000936 (Box 3)
    Borrowing the name
  - Pasha Hayati Hassid- The Turkish Tom Thumb with carriage; UK, 1909; MS254.000937 (Box 3)
    Pasha with a carriage
  - Pasha Hayati Hassid at Tiny Town, 1910; MS254.000938 (Box 3)
    Various characters
  - "Tom Thumb"; Smallest Man in Existence; UK, 1905; MS254.000939 (Box 3)
    Small person
  - Conrad Kruger; Official Announcer at Midget City, Dreamland, Coney Island; show announcement on back, 1905; MS254.000940 (Box 3)
    Postcard with announcement for Mrs. Tom Thumb Show printed on back
  - Mrs. Tom Thumb's carriage with Gentry Bros. Circus, Lemars, Iowa, 1910; MS254.000941 (Box 3)
    Carriage with driver
  - Dolletta with her children and carriage; info on back, 1910; MS254.000942 (Box 3)
    World'ssmallest mother; info on back
  - Angus McAskill, The Nova Scotia Giant with Commodore Nutt; copy of earlier photo, 1863 -- 1930; MS254.000943 (Box 3)
    Often mis-identified as McAskill and Tom Thumb
  - The Irish Tom Thumb; UK, 1920; MS254.000944 (Box 3)
    Irish Tom Thumb
  - Admiral F. Thumb, Midget, 1910; MS254.000945 (Box 3)
    Admiral Thumb
  - Tom Thumb, The Oldest Midget in the World; UK, 1910; MS254.000946 (Box 3)
    Another variation on the Tom Thumb name
  - "Tom Thumb"; UK, 1910; MS254.000947 (Box 3)
    Another Tom Thumb
  - Lavinia Warren Doll, 1950; MS254.000948 (Box 3)
    Life size doll of Lavinia at Game Lodge Doll House, Custer, SD
  - Circus Kings, 1960; MS254.000949 (Box 3)
    Ringlings and Barnum and Bailey
  - Captain George Auger, Cardiff Giant, 1910; MS254.000950 (Box 3)
    Auger appeared in a film made with Lavinia Warren in 1915
  - Two Smallest Horses in the World, Tom Thumb and Admiral Dot, 1910; MS254.000951 (Box 3)
    Namesakes
  - Auburn Prison, NY, 1910; MS254.000952 (Box 3)
    The midgets visited the prison at least once; see other photo
  - Tom Thumb Wedding, 1914; MS254.000953 (Box 3)
    Tom with info Thumb Wedding
  - Tom Thumb Wedding II, 1907; MS254.000954 (Box 3)
    Tom Thumb Wedding with info
  - Tom Thumb Wedding III; Lincoln, Iowa 1931, 1931 -- 1983; MS254.000955 (Box 3)
    Tom Thumb Wedding, Lincoln, Iowa, Feb. 27-28, 1931
  - Midget City, Dreamland, Coney Island, 1905; MS254.000956 (Box 3)
    Overview of Midget City
  - Midget City, Dreamland, Coney Island II, 1905; MS254.000957 (Box 3)
    Entrance toMidget City
  - Dreamland Circus, Coney Island, 1905; MS254.000958 (Box 3)
    Dreamland Circus Sideshow
  - General View of Tozman Plaza, Midget City, Coney Island, 1905; MS254.000959 (Box 3)
    Primo and Lavinia lived in Midget City for the summer of 1905
  - A Few Acts in the Tom Thumb Circus, Midget City, 1905; MS254.000960 (Box 3)
    Various midget acts
  - Litle Men and Little Women, Midget City, 1905; MS254.000961 (Box 3)
    Performers in costume
  - The Players in Midget City Opera House, 1905; MS254.000962 (Box 3)
    Looks like Liable and Annie Nelson on the left
  - Little Men and Women; carriages; Midget City, 1905; MS254.000963 (Box 3)
    Fancy carriages
  - Midget City Fire and Police Departments, 1905; MS254.000964 (Box 3)
    Tom Thumb Circus in the background
  - Primo and Lavinia at Midget City; autographed, 1905; MS254.000965 (Box 3)
  - Print of Barnum's American Museum, NY; colored, 1855; MS254.000966 (Box 4)
    From a newspaper; later hand coloring
  - Print,General Tom Thumb in his Carriage; colored, 1846; MS254.000967 (Box 4)
    Dean & Co., Threadneedle
  - Print, General Tom Thumb; Currier and Ives, 1850; MS254.000968 (Box 4)
    Barnum's Gallery of Wonders; based on a dageurreotype by John Plumb
  - Print, Tom Thumb in France with carriage, 1845; MS254.000969 (Box 4)
    Print from French fashion magazine
  - Print, Tom Thumb Marriage by Currier & Ives, 1863; MS254.000970 (Box 4)
    Print of the wedding party
  - Print, parody of Tom Thumb as Jeff Davis; Vanity Fair magazine, 1864; MS254.000971 (Box 4)
    Parody of Jeff Davis asking the French King for assistance
  - Advertisement for Gentry Bros. Show, 1913; MS254.000972 (Box 4)
    Ad from a newspaper for Gentry Show; Lavinia and Primo, and probably Ernesto traveled out West with this show in thw 1890's
  - Personal invitation to visit Strattons in England, 1865; MS254.000973 (Box 9)
    Personal, printed invitation for Major Erlaw to vist the Strattons, staying at Cataldi's Hotel
  - Nutshell Coach on front of ad for Gen. Tom Thumb and Wife, 1880; MS254.000974 (Box 9)
    Handout ad for the show with the Nutshell Coach on the front
  - Ad, Tom Thumb and wife before the crowned heads of Europe, 1880; MS254.000975 (Box 9)
    Handout ad with the couple on a table
  - Chromo ad for Tom Thumb show at Griswold Opera House; Major Newell on front, 1880; MS254.000976 (Box 9)
    Die cut ad for the show with Maor Newell on front
  - Chromo ad for Tom Thumb show at Odd Fellows Hall, 1880; MS254.000977 (Box 9)
    Die cut ad for the show with Marvelous Midget on front
  - Chromo ad for Tom Thumb show at Low's Opera House, 1880; MS254.000978 (Box 9)
    Die cut ad for the show with Royalty on front
  - Chromo ad for Tom Thumb Show with Bingham, ventriloquist on front, 1880; MS254.000979 (Box 9)
    Die cut ad for the show at Low's Opera House
  - Chromo ad for Tom Thumb Show with Zoe Meleke on front, 1880; MS254.000980 (Box 9)
  - Chromo ad for Tom Thumb Show with Zoe Meleke on front II, 1880; MS254.000981 (Box 9)
    Die cut ad for the show at New Grand Opera House
  - Chromo ad for Tom Thumb Show with Whiston on front, 1880; MS254.000982 (Box 9)
  - Chromo ad for Tom Thumb Show with Whiston on front II, 1880; MS254.000983 (Box 9)
    Die cut ad for the show at Griswold Opera House
  - Ad for show at Manchester Opera House, 1888; MS254.000984 (Box 9)
    Lavinia, Primo and Ernesto
  - Ad for Mrs. Gen'l Tom Thumb show at the Music Hall, 1890; MS254.000985 (Box 9)
    Ad for show
  - Ad for Mrs. Tom Thumb Show, 1890; MS254.000986 (Box 9)
    Ad for Grand Matinee
  - Ad for Mrs. Tom Thumb Show; flower motif, 1890; MS254.000987 (Box 9)
    Card with ad on back
  - Ad for Mrs. Tom Thumb Show, flower motif II, 1890; MS254.000988 (Box 9)
  - Souvenir card from Lavinia, Star Theatre, Seattle, Wash., 1895; MS254.000989 (Box 9)
    Lavinia trying to remind the public of who she was